Guide to the Henry Draper Image Collection MC.230
New York University Archives
Henry Draper Image Collection
circa 1870s
New York University Archives
Draper, Henry, 1837-1882
MC.230
81 items in 40 boxes
Henry Draper was a physician and dean of faculty of the Medical Department of the University of the City of New York (now New York University). He was also a pioneer in the field of astrophotography. This collection contains many glass plates of his photographs, many of which are astronomical images. Some slides also relate to his research and teaching at the University.
Conditions Governing Access
Repository permission is required for access. Please contact New York University Archives, 212-998-2641, university-archives@nyu.edu.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Upon Henry Draper's death in 1882 the items in this collection were in his New York laboratory. Draper's sister, Mrs. Antonia Dixon, presented these items to the University. The accession number related to this collection is 82.030.
Arrangement
This finding aid is arranged by subject; however, the collection is housed according to the format's size. The container list provides information on where to locate each object.
Missing Title
Solar spectra
Moon images
X-rays
Draper's observatory and laboratory
NYU
Educational presentation material
Daguerreotype
Fragments
Memorabilia
Biographical note
Henry Draper was born March 7, 1837, to John William Draper and Antonia Coetana de Paiva Pereira Gardner. John William Draper was a doctor, chemist, and professor at the University of the City of New York (now New York University), and his son Henry followed closely in his footsteps. Henry Draper graduated from the Medical Department of the University of the City of New York in 1857. He became a physician at Bellevue Hospital and later returned to the University as a professor and eventually as dean of faculty of the Medical Department. Despite his employment as a doctor, Draper also spent a large amount of time on his passion of astrophotography. He even built his own observatory on his father's estate at Hastings-on-Hudson. Draper was a pioneer in the astrophotography field, directing an expedition to photograph the 1874 transit of Venus and being the first to photograph an astronomical nebula with his image of the Orion Nebula in 1880. He was also interested in spectra, taking the first image of the stellar spectrum in 1872. Draper also invented the slit spectrograph and improved on many photographic tools such as telescope clock drives which are necessary to steady long photographic exposures.
In 1867 Henry Draper married the wealthy socialite Anna Mary Palmer. Not only was she an able laboratory assistant, but she also helped turn their home into a center for celebrities and scientists. Draper was well recognized, receiving honorary law degrees from the University of the City of New York and the University of Wisconsin, a Congressional medal, and election to both the National Academy of Sciences and the Astronomische Gesellschaft. Unfortunately, Draper became ill during a trip to the Rocky Mountains and died of double pleurisy at the age of 45. His wife established the Henry Draper Memorial that awards the Henry Draper Medal for astrophysics and funded the Henry Draper Catalog, which is a massive photographic stellar spectrum survey.
Source: "Henry Draper," in Biographical Encyclopedia of Astronomers, ed. Thomas Hockey (New York: Springer, 2007).
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Fragile materials may only be handled with the assistance of an archivist. Digital surrogates may be created for objects too fragile to handle. Please contact New York University Archives with any questions regarding digital surrogates.
Related Materials
Draper Family Papers (MC 11)
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of primarily glass plates of images taken by Draper and the wooden cabinet where negatives were stored. They include astrophotography images of the moon and solar spectra along with images of sites of Draper's work, such as the University campus and his observatory at Hastings-on-Hudson. Some of these glass slides have been damaged and now only exist in partial fragments. Additionally, this collection contains Draper's collection of lantern slides of historical images and reproductions of his photographs used in educational presentations.
Daguerreotype; Lantern slides; New York University -- Faculty -- 19th century
- Series I: Spectra
  - Brating Carbon Crucible (1), 24 May 1880; cuid1884; Lantern Slide? Glass plate (Box 2)
  - Sulphur (2), 1 June 1878; cuid1885; Glass plate (Box 2)
  - Crucible and Sun (3), 25 April 1880; cuid1886; Glass plate (Box 2)
  - Carbon Crucible (4), 25 April 1880; cuid1887; Glass plate (Box 2)
  - Spectra (5), 6 January 1878; cuid1888; Glass plate (Box 2)
  - Spectra (6), 12 June 18--?; cuid1889; Glass plate (Box 2)
  - Spectra (7), 31 May 18--?; cuid1890; Glass plate (Box 2)
  - Iodine (8), 17 January 1881; cuid1891; Glass plate (Box 2)
  - Maxim (9), 21 January 1881; cuid1892; Glass plate (Box 2)
  - Spectra (10), 5 January 1878; cuid1893; Glass plate (Box 2)
  - Grating (11), 31 May 1880; cuid1894; Glass plate (Box 2)
  - Granite Spectroscope (12), 21 May 1880; cuid1895; Glass plate (Box 2)
  - Spectra (13), 20 March 1878; cuid1896; Glass plate (Box 2)
  - Spectra (14), 19 January ----?; cuid1897; Glass plate (Box 2)
  - Grating Spectroscope (15), 24 May 1880; cuid1898; Glass plate (Box 2)
  - Carbon and Sun (16), 1 May 1880; cuid1899; Glass plate (Box 2)
  - Iodine (17), December 1877; cuid1900; Glass plate (Box 2)
  - Carbon Channeled Spectrum (18), 23 April 1880; cuid1901; Glass plate (Box 2)
  - Carbon In Sun (19), 1 May 1880; cuid1902; Glass plate (Box 2)
  - Carbon Bands Identified (20), 23 April 1880; cuid1903; Glass plate (Box 2)
  - Iron Arc Crucible (21), 23 April 1880; cuid1904; Glass plate (Box 2)
  - Spectrum of Iodine (22), December 1877; cuid1905; Glass plate (Box 2)
  - Spectra (1) - No. 3, 4 April 1879; cuid1906; Wet collodion negative, Glass plate (Box 3)
  - Spectra (2) - No. 2, 26 March 1879; cuid1907; Collodion Wet Negative, Glass plate (Box 3)
  - Spectra (5) - No. 3, March 26, 1879; cuid1908; Collodion Wet Negative, Glass plate (Box 3)
  - Spectra (6), undated; cuid1909; Collodion Wet Negative, Glass plate (Box 3)
  - Spectra (7), undated; cuid1910; Collodion Wet Negative, Glass plate (Box 3)
  - Spectra (8), August 12, 1873; cuid1911; Collodion Wet Negative, Glass plate; Small sticker label: Aug 12, 1873, Midday 5 5. (Box 3)
  - Spectra (9), August 11, 187-; cuid1912; Glass plate; Small label is only partially legible: Aug 11th, 187-, 6 PM, 10th. (Box 3)
  - Spectra (10) - No. 2, 8 March 1879; cuid1913; Collodion Wet Negative, Glass plate; Has the appearance of mold on the glass plate. (Box 3)
  - Spectra (11) - No. 1, 6 April 1879; cuid1914; Collodion wet plate, glass negative (Box 3)
  - Spectra (12) - No. 2, 10 March 1879; cuid1915; Collodion process wet plate, glass negative (Box 3)
  - Spectra (13) - No. 3, 8 March 1879; cuid1916; Collodion process wet plate, glass negative (Box 3)
  - Spectra (14) - No. 1, 8 March 1879; cuid1917; Collodion process wet plate, glass negative; possible evidence of mold. (Box 3)
  - Spectra (15) - No. 1, 3 March 1879; cuid1918; Collodion process, wet plate, glass negative (Box 3)
  - Spectra (16), 19 June 1876; cuid1919; Narrower than the other plates in collection and appears to be a slightly different photographic process. Wet plate, glass negative; Label: difficult to decipher. The number 4/12 appears between two words or abbreviations. Dated 19 June 76. (Box 3)
  - Spectra (17), undated; cuid1920; Lantern slide negative. Unsure of photographic process, possibly some kind of wet plate. (Box 3)
  - Spectra (3), 16 March 1879; cuid1921; Glass plate (Box 3)
  - Grating (2) - No. 3, 23 May 1880; cuid1922; Collodion process wet plate, glass negative (Box 4)
  - Spectra (3), undated; cuid1923; Glass plate negative, dry plate. A and B etched above two different figures. (Box 4)
  - Spectra (5) - No. 2, 12 January 1876; cuid1924; Collodion process wet plate, glass negative; possible evidence of mold. (Box 4)
  - CO2 (6), April 1878; cuid1925; Glass plate (Box 4)
  - Spectra (7), 10 March 1879; cuid1926; Glass plate (Box 4)
  - Spectra (8), 4 April 1879; cuid1927; Glass plate (Box 4)
  - Spectra (9), 6 April 1879; cuid1928; Glass plate (Box 4)
  - Spectra (10), 1 April 1879; cuid1929; Glass plate (Box 4)
  - Spectra (11), 9 March 1879; cuid1930; Glass plate (Box 4)
  - Spectra (12), undated; cuid1931; Glass plate (Box 4)
  - Spectra (13), 15 March 1878; cuid1932; Glass plate (Box 4)
  - Spectra (14), 11 May 1879; cuid1933; Glass plate (Box 4)
  - Spectra (3), undated; cuid1934; Glass plate (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Canis Minoris D2204 (5), undated; cuid1935; Glass plate (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - No. 21; D187; 13 (6), undated; cuid1936; Glass plate (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - No. 22; D204; G; 26 (7), undated; cuid1937; Glass plate (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - 17;0201;12 (1), undated; cuid1938; Glass plate (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - 18;D198;12 (2), undated; cuid1939; Glass plate (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Untitled (3), undated; cuid1940; Glass plate (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - No. 20; D186;13 (4), undated; cuid1941; Glass plate (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - D2205 (5), undated; cuid1942; Glass plate (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Spectra (1), undated; cuid1943; Glass plate (Box 10)
  - Spectra (2), undated; cuid1944; Glass slide (Box 10)
  - Spectra (3), undated; cuid1945; Glass slide (Box 10)
  - Spectra (4), undated; cuid1946; Glass slide (Box 10)
  - Spectra (5), undated; cuid1947; Glass slide (Box 10)
  - Chloride of Tin? Seems to be Nitrogen only (1), 18 April 1877; cuid1948; Glass plate (Box 11)
  - Spectra (3), 16 March 1878; cuid1949; Glass plate (Box 11)
  - Spectra (4), 1878; cuid1950; Glass plate (Box 11)
  - Spectra (5), undated; cuid1951; Glass plate (Box 11)
  - Sulphuretted Hydrogen (6), 14 February 1878; cuid1952; Glass plate (Box 11)
  - Sulphur (7), 1 January 1878; cuid1953; Glass plate (Box 11)
  - Spectrum of CO2-Voighander between slit of plage-Browning prism close to slit (9), February 1877; cuid1954; Glass plate (Box 11)
  - Cyanogen (10), 23 April 1877; cuid1955; Glass plate (Box 11)
  - Leyden (11), 24 March 1877; cuid1956; Glass plate (Box 11)
  - Bromide of Silicon (12), 18 April 1877; cuid1957; Glass plate (Box 11)
  - Hydrogen 2nd ex. of tube 10m-800 sparks red-No. Leyden, 18 March 1877; cuid1958; Glass plate (Box 11)
  - Spectra (14), 14 January ----?; cuid1959; Glass plate (Box 11)
  - Cyanogen (15), 23 April 1876; cuid1960; Glass plate (Box 11)
  - Carbonic Acid (16), 28 April 1877; cuid1961; Glass plate (Box 11)
  - Hydrogen 800 ten? sparks per minute-Browning of prisms (17), 14 February 1877; cuid1962; Glass plate (Box 11)
  - Spectra (18), undated; cuid1963; Glass plate (Box 11)
  - Sun 5S Nitrogen 800 ten inch sparks per minute, 17 February 1877; cuid1964; Glass plate (Box 11)
  - Hydrogen-No Leyden (20), undated; cuid1965; Glass plate (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Hydrogen-No Leyden (21), 3 March 1877; cuid1966; Glass plate (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Hydrogen 15m ex. 800 sparks per minute-No Leyden-No. 2 (22), 1 March 1877; cuid1967; Glass plate (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Hydrogen-No Leyden-15m ex...No.3 (23), 1 March 1877; cuid1968; Glass plate (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Leyden (24), undated; cuid1969; Glass plate (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Hydrogen-800 ten inch sparks per minute-10m ex.- Browning of prism (25), 14 February 1877; cuid1970; Glass plate (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Spectrum of Sulphuret of L? (26), 21 May 1877; cuid1971; Glass plate (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Brass (27), 25 February ----?; cuid1972; Glass plate (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Sulphur (28), 1 January 1878; cuid1973; Glass plate (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Stellar Spectra Dispersion ~90A/mm-11 glass slide, circa 1879; cuid1974 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Stellar Spectra Dispersion ~90A/mm-11 glass slide, circa 1879; cuid14876 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Stellar Spectra Dispersion ~90A/mm-11 glass slide, circa 1879; cuid14877 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Stellar Spectra Dispersion ~90A/mm-11 glass slide, circa 1879; cuid14878 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Stellar Spectra Dispersion ~90A/mm-11 glass slide, circa 1879; cuid14879 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Stellar Spectra Dispersion ~90A/mm-11 glass slide, circa 1879; cuid14880 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Stellar Spectra Dispersion ~90A/mm-11 glass slide, circa 1879; cuid14881 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Stellar Spectra Dispersion ~90A/mm-11 glass slide, circa 1879; cuid14882 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Stellar Spectra Dispersion ~90A/mm-11 glass slide, circa 1879; cuid14883 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Stellar Spectra Dispersion ~90A/mm-11 glass slide, circa 1879; cuid14884 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Stellar Spectra Dispersion ~90A/mm-11 glass slide, circa 1879; cuid14885 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Eastman, 11 March 1881; cuid1975; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - 8648 carbon ore, 1 March 1881; cuid1976; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - No. 2 5m slit 14/5000, 24 February 1881; cuid1977; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - 90S carbon ore, 1 March 1881; cuid1978; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Photographic experiment no. 1, 22 February 1881; cuid1979; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Painted on black, 11 March 1881; cuid1980; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Old lantern pyrogallic experiments, 7 April 1881; cuid1981; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Old lantern oxalate experiment, 7 April 1881; cuid1982; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Old lantern oxalate experiment, 7 April 1881; cuid1983; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Photographic experiment no. 2, 6 February 1881; cuid1984; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Carbon ore 90S, 25 February 1881; cuid1985; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Carbon ore, 1 March 1881; cuid1986; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Photographic experiment no. 2, 22 February 1881; cuid1987; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Photographic experiment, 7 April 1881; cuid1988; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Exposed oxidate, 7 April 1881; cuid1989; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Photographic experiment, 19 April 1881; cuid1990; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Photographic experiment, 23 April 1881; cuid1991; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Photographic experiment, 17 April 1881; cuid1992; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Photographic experiment, 6 February 1881; cuid1993; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Carbon ore prisms, 20 February 1881; cuid1994; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - No. 1 90S, 24 February 1881; cuid1996; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Sun 10S, 11 June 1882; cuid1995; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - New Eastman oxalate, 7 April 1881; cuid1997; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - New Eastman No. 1 Experiment, 6 April 1881; cuid1998; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Old Eastman No. 2 Experiment, 6 April 1881; cuid1999; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Old Eastman No. 1 Experiment, 6 April 1881; cuid2000; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - New Eastman No. 2 Experiment, 5 April 1881; cuid2001; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Old Lantern No. 2 Experiment, 5 April 1881; cuid2002; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Photographic experiment, undated; cuid2003; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - New Eastman No. 1 Experiment, 5 April 1881; cuid2004; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - New Eastman No. 2 Experiment, 6 April 1881; cuid2005; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Portrait of a woman, undated; cuid2006; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - 4 portraits of a man, undated; cuid2007; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Photographic experiment, 29 January 1881; cuid2008; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Photographic experiment grating, 13 February 1881; cuid2009; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Photographic experiment no. 2, 18 January 1881; cuid2010; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Photographic experiment ex 60th, 22 January 1881; cuid2011; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Sun prisms, 20 February 1881; cuid2012; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Photographic experiment grating, 13 February 1881; cuid2013; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Photographic experiment, 23 January 1881; cuid2014; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Photographic experiment no. 1, 18 January 1881; cuid2015; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Puppis - Spectrum 3923-4505, undated; cuid2016; Cardboard (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Carbon, 10 July 1882; cuid2017; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Focus photography, 11 March 1882; cuid2018; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Sun 10^5 Oxygen, 11 June 1882; cuid2019; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Photographic experiment no. 1, 28 May 1882; cuid2020; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Photographic experiment no. 2, 28 May 1882; cuid2021; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Photographic experiment, 11 April 1881; cuid2022; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Photographic experiment, undated; cuid2023; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Sun and Air, undated; cuid2024; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - (?) that I have and in stellar (?) up to present, 11 March 1881; cuid2025; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Copy of stellar emission spectrum no. 23-probably a reproduction of Draper's own plate (01), undated; cuid2026; Glass plate (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Print of solar spectrum-"Discovery of oxygen in the sun" (2), 1876; cuid2027; Glass plate (Box 34, Folder 2)
    Scope and Contents
    Upper part of photograph is spectrum of sun. Lower part is spectrum of oxygen and nitrogen of air. This is the illustration (probably the original for the reproduction) in the paper about oxygen in the sun (J. Franklin Institute vol. 74).
  - Solar? spectrum "D660" (3), undated; cuid2028; Glass plate (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Objective prism plate (4), undated; cuid2029; Glass plate (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Spectrum no. 24 (5), undated; cuid2030; Glass plate (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Solar? spectrum (6), undated; cuid2031; Glass plate (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - Objective prism plate (7), undated; cuid2032; Glass plate (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - Objective prism plate-probably Pleiades (8), undated; cuid2033; Glass plate (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - Objective prism plate (9), undated; cuid2034; Glass plate (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - Objective prism plate-star field (10), undated; cuid2035; Glass plate (Box 34, Folder 10)
  - Objective prism plate (11), undated; cuid2036; Glass plate (Box 34, Folder 11)
  - Objective prism plate (12), undated; cuid2037; Glass plate (Box 34, Folder 12)
  - Objective prism plate-Arcturus (13), undated; cuid2038; Glass plate (Box 34, Folder 13)
  - No image, undated; cuid2039; Glass plate (Box 34, Folder 14)
  - Copy of a corona taken by A. Clark at Criston (2), 29 July 1878; cuid2040; Glass plate negative (on emulsion) (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - Solar spectrum (4), 15 May 1879; cuid2041; Glass plate negative (broken) (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - Solar spectrum (5), 2 April 1879; cuid2042; Glass plate negative (broken) (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - Enlarged copy of solar spectrum (6), undated; cuid2043; Glass plate negative (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - Sun and Air (Leyden spark) with coincidence of oxygen lines with "bright lines" in the sun (7), 1876; cuid2044; Glass plate negative (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - Solar spectrum (8), 6 January 1879; cuid2045; Glass plate negative (Box 37, Folder 8)
  - Solar spectrum (9), 1 April 1879; cuid2046; Glass plate negative (Box 37, Folder 9)
  - Solar spectrum (10), 2 April 1879; cuid2047; Glass plate negative (Box 37, Folder 10)
  - Solar spectrum (11), undated; cuid2048; Glass plate negative (Box 37, Folder 11)
  - Solar consparison spectrum (12), undated; cuid2049; Glass plate negative (Box 37, Folder 12)
  - Solar spectrum with comparison spectrum (13), 6 April 1878; cuid2050; Glass plate negative (Box 37, Folder 13)
  - Solar spectrum with comparison spectrum (14), 6 April 1878; cuid2051; Glass plate negative (Box 37, Folder 14)
  - Solar corona (19), 1878; cuid2052; Glass plate (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - Solar spectrum with comparison spectrum (20), undated; cuid2053; Glass plate negative (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - Fluoride of silicon laboratory spectrum (21), 23 April 1877; cuid2054; Glass plate negative (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - Bromide of silicon laboratory spectrum (22), 23 April 1879; cuid2055; Glass plate negative (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - Coal gas laboratory spectrum (23), undated; cuid2056; Glass plate negative (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - Coal gas laboratory spectrum (24), 14 February 1878; cuid2057; Glass plate negative (Box 38, Folder 9)
  - Carbon laboratory spectrum (25), 25 April 1880; cuid2058; Glass plate negative (Box 38, Folder 10)
  - Laboratory spectrum (26), 19 April 1878; cuid2059; Glass plate negative (Box 38, Folder 11)
  - Carbonic acid laboratory spectrum (27), 3 May 1877; cuid2060; Glass plate negative (Box 38, Folder 12)
  - Solar spectrum with comparison spectrum (28), 15 April 1877; cuid2061; Glass plate negative (Box 38, Folder 13)
  - Spectrum (29), 1877; cuid2062; Glass plate negative (Box 38, Folder 14)
  - Laboratory spectrum (30), 17 April 1877; cuid2063; Glass plate negative (Box 38, Folder 15)
  - Solar spectrum with nitrogen laboratory spectrum (31), 11 April 1877; cuid2064; Glass plate negative (Box 39)
  - Solar spectrum with comparison spectrum (32), 18 April 1878; cuid2065; Glass plate negative (Box 39)
  - Carbonic acid laboratory spectrum (33), 1 May 1877; cuid2066; Glass plate negative (Box 39)
  - Solar spectrum with nitrogen lab spectrum for comparison (34), 1 April 1877; cuid2067; Glass plate negative (Box 39)
  - Solar spectrum with comparison (35), undated; cuid2068; Glass plate negative (Box 39)
  - Coal gas laboratory spectrum (36), 1878; cuid2069; Glass plate negative (Box 39)
  - Solar spectrum with comparison CO2 identifications (37), 15 April 1877; cuid2070; Glass plate negative (Box 39)
  - Solar spectrum with air for comparison (38), 7 April 1877; cuid2071; Glass plate negative (Box 39)
  - Cyanogen laboratoy spectrum (39), 17 April 1877; cuid2072; Glass plate negative (Box 39)
  - Solar spectrum with comparison identification (40), 24 March 1877; cuid2073; Glass plate negative (Box 39)
  - Solar spectrum with comparison (41), 18 February 1877; cuid2074; Glass plate negative (Box 39)
  - Solar spectrum with comparison (42), 6 April 1878; cuid2075; Glass plate negative (Box 39)
  - Solar spectrum with CO2 (43), 3 April 1877; cuid2076; Glass plate negative (Box 39)
  - Solar spectrum with comparison (44), 16 March 1878; cuid2077; Glass plate negative (Box 39)
  - Solar spectrum with comparison (45), 29 May 1877; cuid2078; Glass plate negative (Box 39)
  - Bromide of silicon laboratory spectrum (46), 23 April 1877; cuid2079; Glass plate negative (Box 39)
- Series II: X-Rays
  - X-Ray (2), undated; cuid14543; Glass plate (Box 7)
  - X-Ray (3), undated; cuid14544; Glass plate (Box 7)
  - X-Ray (4), undated; cuid14545; Glass plate (Box 7)
  - X-Ray (5), undated; cuid14546; Glass plate (Box 7)
  - X-Ray (6), undated; cuid14547; Glass plate (Box 7)
  - X-Ray (7), undated; cuid14548; Glass plate (Box 7)
  - X-Ray (8), undated; cuid14549; Glass plate (Box 7)
- Series III: Moon Images
  - Last Quarter Moon (1), 24 August 1872; cuid14550; Glass plate (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Moon Photo taken with 28" telescope (1), 1872; cuid14551; Glass plate (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Moon Photo taken with 28" telescope (2), 1872; cuid14552; Glass plate (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Moon Photo taken with 28" telescope (3), 1872; cuid14553; Glass plate (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Moon Photo taken with 28" telescope (4), 1872; cuid14554; Glass plate (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Moon Photo taken with 28" telescope (5), 1872; cuid14555; Glass plate (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Moon Photo taken with 28" telescope (6), 1872; cuid14556; Glass plate (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Moon Photo taken with 28" telescope (7), 1872; cuid14557; Glass plate (Box 1, Folder 13)